<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knock knock!</title>
    <description>My personal thoughts. Mostly babbling. Sometimes technical.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 22:47:45 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 22:47:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migrate Data From MySQL to Oracle Database</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had a task to convert a database from MySQL to Oracle. I am not sure how many of the records would a database could be call &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; but this one has 15 tables; few of them have 2-5 million rows, and one has over 20 million. It was a fun time for me figuring out the “best” method to deal with the situation. It is definitely not the best method for everyone, but I think it would be useful for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My scenario:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I DO NOT have admin access to the Oracle database server and use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/developer-tools/sql-developer/overview/index.html&quot; title=&quot;Oracle SQL Developer Homepage&quot;&gt;SQL Developer&lt;/a&gt; to connect to the database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I DO have admin access to the MySQL server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;convert-tables-structures&quot;&gt;Convert tables’ structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step can be done in various methods, I suppose. However, I found a program called &lt;a href=&quot;http://razorsql.com/&quot; title=&quot;RazorSQL Homepage&quot;&gt;RazorSQL&lt;/a&gt; that can deal with various types of database, including MySQL and Oracle. When I open connections to both databases, I can actually use the Convert Table(s) method provided by RazorSQL to convert both table structure and data between types of database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I use it to convert only the table structures (the reason not to convert the data also will be explained shortly). All you need to do is to choose the MySQL database, right-click the database then “Tables” on the left sidebar and choose “Database Conversion &amp;gt; Convert [Multiple] Table” with the configuration similar to this screenshot, specifying connection to the Oracle database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/RazorSQL_Convert_Tables.png&quot; alt=&quot;Convert Table Structures with RazorSQL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;export-the-data&quot;&gt;Export the data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the RazorSQL program does provide the data conversion. However, the method was not so good, in my opinion. I failed everytime I tried after a few thousand of records. I guess it is not stable enough, or it is not for like million-record tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenario above posed the problem for the that I can only import the data to the Oracle database with import method using CSV files. In fact, I do not know if Oracle provide a command-line interface for administrator to quickly import data like MySQL or not. I am new to Oracle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely I could use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mysqldump&lt;/code&gt; to rip off data from the MySQL server, which is the fastest method I have known of. However, for some reason, I could not get the field delimiter and special character escaping in the CSV exported with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mysqldump&lt;/code&gt; to be imported properly into the Oracle database, so I ended up using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phpmyadmin.net/home_page/index.php&quot; title=&quot;PhpMyAdmin Homepage&quot;&gt;PhpMyAdmin&lt;/a&gt; to export the data. With millions of row to be exported, I needed to extend the time for the PHP script to execute and mentioned it on my &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/02/19/increase-execution-time-for-phpmyadmin-tasks.html&quot; title=&quot;My other post on extending PHP execution time&quot;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having that execution time resolved, this export step is no hassle. Just go to PhpMyAdmin and choose “Export” with Quick method and format of ouput file is “CSV”, and you will have data files ready to be imported by SQL Developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-the-import-wizard&quot;&gt;Choose the import wizard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be under the “Actions” menu when you open a table. It will ask you to point to the exported CSV file. You can also use some other file format as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xls&lt;/code&gt; of Microsoft Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/SQL_Developer_Import_Data.png&quot; alt=&quot;SQL Developer Actions Menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specify-import-options-for-the-csv-file-pointed-step-1-of-the-wizard&quot;&gt;Specify import options for the CSV file pointed (step 1 of the wizard)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what you should care about might only the two things: the header option (to tell if you have the first row as the fields’ headers or not), and the encoding of the file (where I chose UTF-8 for best handling of special, foreign characters).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Oracle_Import_Wizard.png&quot; alt=&quot;First step Import Wizard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-the-correct-mapping-to-the-table-fields-being-imported-into-step-4-of-the-wizard&quot;&gt;Choose the correct mapping to the table fields being imported into (step 4 of the wizard)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2 &amp;amp; 3 &amp;amp; 5 of the wizard have nothing special, just click “Next”. In step 4, you need to correctly map the fields in the CSV file to the fields in the table. I had CSV files with no header row, so I specified the mapping method to be “Position”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Column_Mapping.png&quot; alt=&quot;Map the column&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-the-import&quot;&gt;Start the import!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the import speed greatly depended on the speed of the network I was using to connect to the Oracle database. When I was on a “slow” 10Mbps network, it took me about 30 minutes to finish importing of 2.7 million records. With similar amount of time, when I was on a high speed network (that closes to the database, actually), SQL Developer could import over 20 million rows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend to do this import task when you have plenty of time, say, overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading this! I hope it will help database newbies like me to get an overview of converting data from MySQL to Oracle database. Please do not hesitate to leave comments!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 12:25:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/03/02/migrate-data-from-mysql-to-oracle-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/03/02/migrate-data-from-mysql-to-oracle-database.html</guid>
        
        <category>MySQL,</category>
        
        <category>Oracle,</category>
        
        <category>DBMS</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Increase Execution Time for PhpMyAdmin Tasks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might have some time-consuming tasks to perform on PhpMyAdmin (I assume for some reasons, you do not have the access to MySQL command-line tools, which is much faster), but the web-based app does not let you get what you wanted because of the limit in execution time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, a PHP script will be executed for a limited time set by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;php.ini&lt;/code&gt; directive &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;max_execution_time&lt;/code&gt; (default = 30 seconds). However, PhpMyAdmin uses its own configuration value. That is why you &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; simply increase the value in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;php.ini&lt;/code&gt; file to tell PhpMyAdmin to run longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I figured out where and what to set the configuration value for PhpMyAdmin. You need to open the file &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config.inc.php&lt;/code&gt; in PhpMyAdmin root director and add the following line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot; data-lang=&quot;php&quot;&gt;$cfg['ExecTimeLimit'] = 300;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;300&lt;/code&gt; is the number of seconds you want the scrip to execute. For unlimited execution time, leave it as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all you need to leave PhpMyAdmin with more time to perform tasks like export or import. In my case, I needed to export a table with about 20 Mil records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to leave comments. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1263680/maximum-execution-time-in-phpmyadmin&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1263680/maximum-execution-time-in-phpmyadmin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 14:53:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/02/19/increase-execution-time-for-phpmyadmin-tasks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/02/19/increase-execution-time-for-phpmyadmin-tasks.html</guid>
        
        <category>PHP,</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resolve Google Chrome Update Error 12 on OS X</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Update server not available (error: 12)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most annoying problems I have got with Google Chrome browser until I finally figure out the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is many time when I Chrome reported it had failed to update to latest version. Even when I manually updated it, it seemed to be in good shape for a while before it became &lt;em&gt;non-updateable&lt;/em&gt; again. The general error message led me to many posts/questions across the Internet but almost nothing helped. Eventually, when I read a post saying something about &lt;strong&gt;missing language files&lt;/strong&gt;, I realized that I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://macpaw.com/cleanmymac&quot; title=&quot;CleanMyMac Application Homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CleanMyMac&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to strip out some of the languages that I never use in both OS X and application I installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to manually update Google Chrome and &lt;strong&gt;not to touch its language files&lt;/strong&gt; again. The great thing comes! I have never encountered the error ever since!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are using any kind of applications to remove unused language files (I know another app call &lt;a href=&quot;http://monolingual.sourceforge.net/&quot; title=&quot;Monolingual Mac Application Homepage&quot;&gt;Monolingual&lt;/a&gt;) from your apps, please remember to leave Google Chrome alone! Otherwise, you might not be updated to its latest version any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that it is a bit hard to figure out this problem initially, so I would like to share the information here for those who have not resolved it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 11:20:28 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/02/18/resolve-google-chrome-update-error-12-on-os-x.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/02/18/resolve-google-chrome-update-error-12-on-os-x.html</guid>
        
        <category>Google</category>
        
        <category>Chrome,</category>
        
        <category>OS</category>
        
        <category>X,</category>
        
        <category>Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configure PHP-FPM Status Page for ServerDensity Monitoring</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have to configure my account at &lt;strong&gt;ServerDensity&lt;/strong&gt; to monitor PHP-FPM activities on one of my servers. It came out that there’s not so many tutorials on how to setup PHP-FPM status page. This is the key to the problem of monitoring PHP-FPM via &lt;a href=&quot;http://plugins.serverdensity.com/php-fpm/&quot;&gt;ServerDensity plugin&lt;/a&gt;. From what I’ve experienced, I hope I could provide a good reference for those who are looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first things first!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;STEP 1:&lt;/em&gt; Enable PHP-FPM status page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find and enable status page in PHP-FPM configuration file. My server is Ubuntu so the configuration files for PHP-FPM are located at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/php5/fpm/&lt;/code&gt;. As PHP-FPM processes are divided by &lt;em&gt;pool&lt;/em&gt;, so status page is also “pool-specific” and should be at pool config files at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/php5/fpm/pool.d/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default pool for PHP-FPM is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; so I am going to edit the file &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www.conf&lt;/code&gt; to enable status page for this pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a text editor, find the text “pm.status_path” and you may see there’s already a default value for this, but disabled. You can enable the option by simply removing the semicolon at the beginning of the line, having:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pm.status_path = /status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you can access to a page, which will show you information about currently running PHP-FPM processes, at the address &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://yourwebservername/status&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save the file and the first step is finished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;STEP 2:&lt;/em&gt; Configuring nginx to actually have access to status page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I am using a Ubuntu server so nginx configuration files in my case are stored at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/nginx/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu manages configuration of sites hosted by means of “VirtualHost”, placed in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/nginx/sites-enabled/&lt;/code&gt;. Howerver, for the purpose of management, we only need the PHP-FPM status page to be accessible from localhost (and the ServerDensity plugin will do so), so it’s reasonable to add a location block to a global configuration file at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/nginx/conf.d/default.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;location /status {
	fastcgi_pass 127.0.0.1:9000;
	fastcgi_index index.php;
	fastcgi_param  SCRIPT_FILENAME $document_root$fastcgi_script_name;
	include fastcgi_params;
	allow 127.0.0.1;
	deny all;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save the file, reload nginx server with the command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/init.d/nginx reload&lt;/code&gt; and you will be able to access PHP-FPM status page at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1/status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could test using the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://127.0.0.1/status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and if you see something like this, you are all set!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;accepted conn:   123
pool:             www
process manager:  dynamic
idle processes:   9
active processes: 1
total processes:  10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can just install the &lt;a href=&quot;http://plugins.serverdensity.com/php-fpm/&quot;&gt;PHP-FPM monitoring plugin&lt;/a&gt; by following the on-screen instruction. Wait for a few minutes before you can visually track how the PHP-FPM manages PHP requests to your server :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t see the visual graph of data for PHP-FPM after about 10 minutes, try to add the status page url to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sd-agent&lt;/code&gt; config file (mine at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/sd-agent/config.cfg&lt;/code&gt;). You need a line similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fpm_status_url = http://127.0.0.1/status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restart the sd-agent with the command below (if you are using Debian/Ubuntu) and you will be fine for sure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/sd-agent restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 02:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2012/03/30/configure-php-fpm-status-page-for-serverdensity-monitoring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2012/03/30/configure-php-fpm-status-page-for-serverdensity-monitoring.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nginx,</category>
        
        <category>PHP-FPM,</category>
        
        <category>Monitoring,</category>
        
        <category>Ubuntu,</category>
        
        <category>ServerDensity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Movie Review - Up (2009)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is over one year since the time I saw the film “Up”, a Computer-Generated Imagery (CGI) movie from the association between Disney and PIXAR, but I still can feel exactly the same feelings that I had this day. The film guides its audiences to a heart-touching story about love, hope, and struggles inside each individual to achieve the ultimate goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Up_movie_poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image from Flickr user jdxyw - 4860504888&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story begins with the fortuitous meeting between Carl, a quiet little boy, and an energetic girl named Ellie who has the common interest with him in becoming an explorer just like the famous Charles F. Muntz. Ellie has a desire to have a house that overlooks Paradise Falls in South America. They then wed and live in the house where they first met. One day, when they find they cannot have a child, they decide to save money to have a trip to Paradise Falls, but, for many reasons, they are unable to make it till the day Ellie dies. Living alone in an old house in a developing city and being forced to move, old Carl decides to keep his promise to Ellie by using thousands of balloons to make his house “fly”. Accidentally, he takes a little boy called Russell who is trying to get his final merit badge for “Assisting the Elderly” from Carl, with him to Paradise Falls, where he gets more troubles than he expected. Walking with the floating house to the falls, they meet a beautiful and rarely-seen bird, Kevin, and a dog that can speak, Dug. Subsequently, they discover that Charles Muntz is living near and trying to catch Kevin for his fame. However, Carl only wants to keep his promise by bringing the house, partly burnt by Muntz before, to the falls, leaving Russell and Kevin. But when he eventually reaches the falls, he finds a diary of Ellie in which she thanked him for her greatest adventure of marriage to him. Carl and Russell then help Kevin to escape from Muntz back to her chicks. After returning to the city, Carl goes to Russell’s Senior Explorer ceremony  and presents him with the final badge, the one that Ellie gave him the day they met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many films by PIXAR have proven that they always know how to make a good CGI film with simple and lovely lines of drawing. Apart from these features, “Up” is also a touching story of love. In a world where people seem to do everything to meet their objective, the story about a man who tries to keep his promise to his beloved as well as keep his companions safe is really emotive. Great plot and lovely imageries accompanied by suitable soundtracks make the film one of the best films voted by Internet users (Internet Movie Database).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 14:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/12/10/review-movie-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/12/10/review-movie-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>English,</category>
        
        <category>Review,</category>
        
        <category>Movie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Install Ruby on Rails on Debian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is showing how to install &lt;strong&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/strong&gt; on a Debian-based host and configure** WeBrick** server (bundled with Ruby) to allow access from other hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you have to do is installing Ruby on Rails. It is pretty easy with “apt-get” command in Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sudo&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; apt-get install ruby libzlib-ruby rdoc irb rubygems rails eruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are some errors showed in this stage, you may have to install the “build-essential” package with this command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sudo&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; apt-get install build-essential&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB&lt;/strong&gt;: you have to add &lt;strong&gt;sudo&lt;/strong&gt; before the commands if you are not running as “root” user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes fine, you could create the very first application followed this tutorial from Ruby on Rails wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.rubyonrails.org/getting-started/first-rails-app-walkthrough&quot;&gt;http://wiki.rubyonrails.org/getting-started/first-rails-app-walkthrough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I found a problem as I work with Ruby on Rails installed on a non-GUI server and the &lt;strong&gt;WeBrick&lt;/strong&gt; server always starts with access only for localhost. I means I can only access the server with the URL: &lt;strong&gt;http://localhost:3000&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, I need to access to server from another host in LAN usign LAN IP address like this: &lt;strong&gt;http://192.168.1.234:3000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change this, you could simply call this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /path/to/app/directory
ruby ./script/server -b 192.168.1.234 -p 3000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of this by default:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;ruby ./script/server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, WeBrick server will start with the defined IP address and port&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;Booting WEBrick...
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;Rails 2.1.0 application started on http://192.168.1.234:3000
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt; &lt;/span&gt;Ctrl-C to shutdown server; call with --help &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;options
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;2010-11-06 15:35:55] INFO  WEBrick 1.3.1
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;2010-11-06 15:35:55] INFO  ruby 1.8.7 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;2008-08-11&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; i486-linux
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;2010-11-06 15:35:55] INFO  WEBrick::HTTPServer#start: &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;pid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;2635 &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;3000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 15:19:59 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/11/06/install-ruby-rails-debian.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/11/06/install-ruby-rails-debian.html</guid>
        
        <category>Linux,</category>
        
        <category>Programming,</category>
        
        <category>Ruby</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use Aptana Studio 2.0.4 on Ubuntu 10.04 64-bit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 10.04 code name “Lucid Lynx” has released yesterday with some improvemets. But if you need to use Aptana Studio IDE in the 64-bit version of this easy-to-use linux, there’re some troubles. I think I could share some information of how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-aptana&quot;&gt;1. Installing Aptana&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty easy to have Aptana working on the system. You just have to download Aptana Standalone version from the website (choose 64-bit platform of course):&lt;a href=&quot;http://aptana.org/studio/download&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aptana.org/studio/download&quot;&gt;http://aptana.org/studio/download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After downloading, you’ll see a zip file of about 82.4MB. Unzip it to somewhere in your computer. I unzipped it to my home ~/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; your system must have Java Runtime Environment (JRE) installed to run Aptana. So just type &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;java&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Terminal to see if you have JRE installed. If Terminal says “command not found”, you have to install it with this command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install sun-java6-jre&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When everything is installed successfully, you could go to unzipped folder of Aptana and run the Application by simply double clicking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AptanaStudio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fix-some-problems-with-aptana-and-plugins&quot;&gt;2. Fix some problems with Aptana and Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prob-1-subversion-and-javahl-library&quot;&gt;Prob 1: Subversion and JavaHL Library&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run Aptana Studio and see message like this (if you exit Aptana and then Re-start it, you will not see the message again, but it’s still the problem. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Windows &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Team&lt;/strong&gt;. Click SVN and you will see if the mess is still out there or not):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Failed to load JavaHL Library.
These are the errors that were encountered:
no libsvnjavahl-1 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in &lt;/span&gt;java.library.path
no svnjavahl-1 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in &lt;/span&gt;java.library.path
no svnjavahl &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in &lt;/span&gt;java.library.path
java.library.path &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; /usr/lib/jvm/java-6-openjdk/jre/lib/amd64/server:/usr/lib/jvm/java-6-openjdk/jre/lib/amd64:/usr/lib/jvm/java-6-openjdk/jre/../lib/amd64:/usr/lib64/xulrunner-addons:/usr/java/packages/lib/amd64:/usr/lib/jni:/lib:/usr/lib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This error is sometimes so complicated according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://subclipse.tigris.org/wiki/JavaHL&quot;&gt;Subclipse wiki&lt;/a&gt;. But in my case, a simple fix can be the solution.
 add this line to &lt;strong&gt;AptanaStudio.ini&lt;/strong&gt; in the folder you unzipped from Installation step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;-Djava.library.path&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/usr/lib/jni&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works in my case. Hope it works in yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prob-2-code-assist-shows-white-list&quot;&gt;Prob 2: Code Assist showS white list&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it’s not the white list. It’s a fully-functional Code assist pop-up but with both the Foreground and Background color in white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mess could be fix easily with a little change in &lt;strong&gt;Theme Color&lt;/strong&gt;. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu top Panel&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;System &amp;gt; Preference &amp;gt; Appearance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click Customize and in Color tab, just change the color of Tooltips. I changed Text and Background to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#000000&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#FFFFAF&lt;/code&gt; and found that it’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. These are 2 problems I’ve faced with Ubuntu and Aptana Studio. Hope this article help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I still wonder about the size of menu or tab bar of Aptana. I think it’s too thick. In Windows, Aptana Editor could show 34 lines of code but in Ubuntu it shows only 30 lines. If someone has the fix, please inform me. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 16:17:30 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/05/01/aptana-studio-204-ubuntu-1004-64bit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/05/01/aptana-studio-204-ubuntu-1004-64bit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Aptana</category>
        
        <category>Studio,</category>
        
        <category>Ubuntu,</category>
        
        <category>PHP</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Valuable Tips for English Study</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t overstudy&lt;/strong&gt;. Trying to study too much in &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; session will lower your ability to remember new things. The brain can  only remember so many items at once, and everyone’s brain is different.  For example, some people can remember over 50 new words a week, while  others remember only 3-4. When you feel you’ve had enough, stop and take  a break – give your brain a rest. If you have been studying for many  years, take a break from your studies for a week or two. When you return  to your studies you will find that you can remember much more than  before. Never study more than 3-4 times a week – For example, study &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;day&lt;/strong&gt; and  rest the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Improve your memory&lt;/strong&gt;: The brain is like a muscle.  It needs exercise or it will lose its ability to process and store  information. Set a regular study time for yourself (just like if you  were going to the gym every other &lt;strong&gt;day&lt;/strong&gt;) and keep to your  schedule. Your body clock will prepare the brain for study if it becomes  use to this schedule. If you are having trouble remembering, connect  new words with things you (or others) already have or know. (For  example, I have a wall clock, a calendar and a desk at home, but I don’t  have a TV. My sister has a TV, but she doesn’t have a cellphone. – 5  new nouns of real things I already know about in my life.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Repeat new words out loud&lt;/strong&gt;, until you are sure of  your pronunciation. If possible, record yourself speaking and then  listen to it, while comparing it to your foreign teacher’s voice. (Ask  your teacher for pronunciation help as often as you need.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Syllable stress&lt;/strong&gt;: Break down words into syllables  and remember that each word has only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; syllable which is  stressed. (For example “Study”, Stú ·dy has two syllables, and the  stress is placed on the syllable “Stú”. – some students find it easier  to write down each syllable and mark the stressed &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; with a Vietnamese  tone marker.) Remember basic rules for stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Nouns&lt;/strong&gt;: Find new vocabulary items in your  environment. Use the foreign vocabulary to talk about them, not your  native language. (Seeing/knowing something real will help improve  learning and memory. – See #2 above.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Verbs&lt;/strong&gt;: If your new vocabulary word is a verb, try  to imagine yourself (and others) doing that action. Try making new  sentences using yourself, your friend(s), family, and/or groups of  people using the new verb. (For example: “I swim”, “he swims”, “they  swim”, “we swim” etc.). When you have accomplished that, try to use  three forms of the verb tense. (For example “I eat”, “I ate”, “I have  eaten”.)
&lt;strong&gt;7. Adjectives&lt;/strong&gt;: If your new vocabulary word is an  adjective, use your word knowledge to connect with nouns and make  sentences, describing those items. For example: “a shiny black wooden  table”, “a beautiful gold watch”, “an expensive Nokia cellphone”.  Practice this step with #5 above. (Remember that not all adjectives fit  with all nouns.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Grammar&lt;/strong&gt;: Remember grammar structure - (subject +  verb + object). Try to remember where certain words go, i.e., adjectives  go before the noun, the verb “to be” goes after the subject, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Make notes&lt;/strong&gt; in class: Keep a class notebook. The  teacher will usually write a grammar or pronunciation point down on the  board for you. You should keep a record of what each class is about.  Copying the class whiteboard to paper is &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; way to remember exactly  what you studied, and it’s easier to review later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Keep a pocket notebook with you&lt;/strong&gt; wherever you go.  When you see something that you haven’t studied yet, write it down (in  your language). When you get home, look-it up in the dictionary (always  use more than &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt;) and write the meaning down (in English) next to your  native word. By using these visual and writing skills it will help you  in the learning process and prevent spelling errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collected from UpdateSofts forum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 10:32:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/04/14/valuable-tips-for-english-study.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/04/14/valuable-tips-for-english-study.html</guid>
        
        <category>English,</category>
        
        <category>Study</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configure Network Interfaces with Configuration Files on Linux?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will show you some basic steps to configure your network interface in Linux using configuration files. This skill is very useful, especially when the &lt;strong&gt;GUI&lt;/strong&gt; does not work anymore. You can use some text editor in linux like &lt;strong&gt;VIM&lt;/strong&gt; to edit the files. It’s easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of commands are applied for &lt;strong&gt;RHEL&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Debian based&lt;/strong&gt; Linux OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 3 steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;locate-the-network-configuration-file&quot;&gt;1. Locate the network configuration file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- RHEL/CentOS/Fedora:&lt;/strong&gt; each interface has it own configuration file like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-&amp;lt;interface_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB&lt;/strong&gt;: interface_name: as usual it would be like eth0, eth1, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Debian/Ubuntu:&lt;/strong&gt;all the interfaces in computer have ONE common configuration file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;/etc/network/interfaces&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;determine-how-ip-address-is-assigned&quot;&gt;2. Determine how IP address is assigned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-  DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol): **IP address will be assigned automatically by DHCP server (in a home/small network, DHCP server is your Router)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RHEL/CentOS/Fedora:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; edit configuration file located in Step 1 to:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;DEVICE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;eth0
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ONBOOT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;yes
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;BOOTPROTO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;dhcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian/Ubuntu:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; add below lines to configuration file located in Step 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;auto eth0
iface eth0 inet dhcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Static IP (mean you have to choose a properly IP address and configure it to your PC):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RHEL/CentOS/Fedora:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; edit configuration file located in Step 1 to:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;DEVICE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;eth0
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;BOOTPROTO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;static
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;IPADDR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;192.168.1.200
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;NETMASK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;255.255.255.0
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;GATEWAY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;192.168.1.1
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ONBOOT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian/Ubuntu:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;add below lines to configuration file located in Step 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;auto eth0
iface eth0 inet static
address 192.168.1.200
netmask 255.255.255.0
broadcast 192.168.1.255
network 192.168.1.0
gateway 192.168.1.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all lines are quite clear. If you want to know what exactly they are, please visit the 2 links I paste at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;add-dns-configuration-only-when--static-ip-used-in-step-2&quot;&gt;3. Add DNS configuration (only when  Static IP used in Step 2)**&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Locate file &lt;strong&gt;/etc/resolv.conf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add these lines to the file&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;nameserve 208.67.222.222 - example IP address of primary name server
nameserver 208.67.220.220 - example IP address of secondary name  server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;restart-network-service-for-applying-new-configuration&quot;&gt;4. Restart network service for applying new configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RHEL/CentOS/Fedora:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; use the following command as &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;/etc/init.d/network restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debian/Ubuntu:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; you might need to enter root password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo /etc/init.d/networking restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s done. Start pinging google.com to check your network is working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit 2 links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yolinux.com/TUTORIALS/LinuxTutorialNetworking.html#CONFIGFILES&quot;&gt;http://www.yolinux.com/TUTORIALS/LinuxTutorialNetworking.html#CONFIGFILES&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redhat.com/docs/manuals/linux/RHL-8.0-Manual/ref-guide/s1-networkscripts-interfaces.html&quot;&gt;http://www.redhat.com/docs/manuals/linux/RHL-8.0-Manual/ref-guide/s1-networkscripts-interfaces.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 11:12:15 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/04/13/configure-network-interfaces-configuration-files-linux.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/04/13/configure-network-interfaces-configuration-files-linux.html</guid>
        
        <category>Linux,</category>
        
        <category>Networking,</category>
        
        <category>Command-Line</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GNS3 Network Device List problem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNS3&lt;/strong&gt; is a graphical network simulator that allows  simulation of complex networks, which is strongly linked with: Dynamips, Dynagen and Qemu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GNS3 is an excellent complementary tool to real labs for network  engineers, administrators and people wanting to pass certifications such  as &lt;strong&gt;CCNA, CCNP, CCIP, CCIE, JNCIA, JNCIS, JNCIE&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;features-overview&quot;&gt;Features overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design of high quality and complex network  topologies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emulation of many Cisco IOS router platforms, IPS,  PIX and ASA firewalls, JunOS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simulation of simple Ethernet, ATM and Frame Relay  switches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connection of the simulated network to the real  world!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Packet capture using Wireshark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GNS3 works flawlessly with Windows XP, but in the new version of Microsoft OS: Windows Vista and Windows 7, they need some configures. One of the most annoying thing is NPF Service that helps Network Device List to list all the networks available in computer. This service is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;STOP by default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and sometimes user cannot find where to turn it on. There’s the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;Computer &amp;gt; Manager &amp;gt; Device Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view Hidden devices, go to menu &lt;strong&gt;View &amp;gt; Show hidden devices&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the driver &lt;strong&gt;NetGroup Packet Filter Driver&lt;/strong&gt;. Right click on the driver, move to tab Driver. Here you can** Start/Stop** the driver and change &lt;strong&gt;Startup mode to Automatically&lt;/strong&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Device_man.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Windows 7 Device Manager&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s done. Easy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope that help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update-april-17-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE April 17, 2010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another method to temporarily activate NPF driver (must do each time computer starts)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start &lt;strong&gt;Command Prompt&lt;/strong&gt; as Administrator&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;C:\Windows\System32&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Run the command: &lt;strong&gt;net start npf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see the line: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The NetGroup Packet Filter Driver service was  started successfully.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s fine. You can view network device list immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 06:47:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2010/04/13/gns3-network-device-list-problem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2010/04/13/gns3-network-device-list-problem.html</guid>
        
        <category>CCNA,</category>
        
        <category>CCNP,</category>
        
        <category>GNS3,</category>
        
        <category>Cisco,</category>
        
        <category>Networking,</category>
        
        <category>Simulation,</category>
        
        <category>Windows</category>
        
        <category>7</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
